Today's video is dedicated to
this comment of Mr. Prashant ji. Prashant ji, thank you
very much for your comment. Thank you
very much. You have commented in the comment area of ​​the
video of Savings Suraksha Plan of ICC Prudential Life.
If
you also want to understand the details of Savings Suraksha Plan
with Dharan, then
check the description of today's video.
You will get the link of the video of this plan,
which will save your time. Check it
and tell us in the comment area, on
which topic do you want the video or about which
plan do you want to know.
Every video on the channel has come
continuously as per your suggestions and questions, so stay
connected with us. Like the video and do
not forget to turn on the notification bell by subscribing to the channel. Hello everyone, a
very warm welcome to all of you. You are watching
UD Real. I am your own personal
advisor Amit Raj Sharma. Let us start today's video
and know directly about the plan. The
plan is the
Cashback Plan of ICC Prudential Life Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a non-paying participating
money back life insurance plan. If we
explain it in simple words, our
investment  It is done here, that is, but the
premium that we pay here will
not be market related because the
company will not invest our premium in equity stocks. If we
participate, then
every year at the end of the circular year, if the company
announces a bonus, then we will definitely be
paid. Along with this,
we will be given money back at regular intervals,
which will be as per the policy term, that is, the
percentage will be as per the positive we select. We
also get the benefit of guaranteed additions in the plan,
so that we also get the maturity benefit and lump
sum simultaneously. Now, since this is a life
insurance plan, you all know
that during the policy term, the
life insurance of the insured will also be there, that is, if something happens to them, then the
life tax amount will be
paid to the nominee. The policy will be closed. We will
understand how the benefit will be reduced later. Now, let us know about the
eligibility criteria of ICC Prudential Life's cash back plan.
If you want to take the cash back plan, then the age
limit was kept from 16 years to 55 years. The
maturity limit is further  It was kept
from 31 years to 70 years, the minimum sum assured
limit here was ₹75000 and the maximum
limit depended on the company as to
how much they could give you, how much proof they provide. The
minimum annual premium
limit is ₹6000, the maximum premium
limit depends on what you see,
how much sum assured you can get
under this plan. Now let us know about the benefits of ICC
Prudential Life's cash back plan. If you
watch the video on full screen in high resolution, you will come to know that there are
two policy term options in the plan, 15 years and 20
years and you have to pay the premium for the same number of years as you take a positive term of 15 years.
If you take a positive term of 15 years, then
at the end of the third year of the policy, you get
10% cash back of the basic sum assured, that is, you get
money back and if
we take a positive term of 20 years, then
at the end of the fourth year of the policy, you will get 10% money
back of the basic sum assured. 15 years  With a policy term of 15 years, you get a
second money back
at the end of the 4th year of the policy and with a policy term of 20 years, you will get a
second money back at the
end of the 8th year of the policy term. There is only
one and that is 15% of your basic sum assured. If you
take a positive term of 15 years, then
you will get a cashback for the third time at the end of the 9th year of the policy.
And if you take a positive term of 20 years, then
you will get a cashback at the end of 12th year of the policy. The
percentage will be the same,
you will get a cashback of 20%. If you
take a positive term of 15 years, then
at the end of 12th year of the policy, you will get a
cashback of 25% of the basic sum assured, i.e. money back. If
you have taken a policy term of 20 years, then
at the end of the 12th year of the policy,
you will get a cashback of 25% of the basic sum assured.
After this, you get maturity benefits. If
you have a positive term of 15 years, then at the
end of the 15th year of the policy, you will get a
guarantee addition of 50% of the basic sum assured
plus vesting bonus, i.e. simple reverse.  It is
from the same period that even in the case of 20 years policy term,
50% of the basic sum assured
plus vesting bonus is guaranteed addition which is
available whenever all the premiums are paid.
What is the guaranteed addition? It is
3.5% of the basic sum assured which is
available in the first year of the policy and
you get this in place of compound interest.
Right, after this you get a simple reversionary bonus. The
company itself tells you the
amount of bonus and the bonus keeps accumulating
from the fifth year of the policy
till the end of the policy maturity. Through this
item, the debt
benefit is very simple because
understand it in an endowment policy in a way. If there is a
guaranteed addition plus bonus, that is, if there is a
simple reversionary bonus, then you will get it.
Right, now to understand the calculation of the example, let's take the
cashback benefits of ICC Prudential Life as an example
here. Let's take a
man whose age is 30 years.
He took a 15-year loan here, so
you know that  In the positive of 15 years, the
premium payment term i.e. PPT is of 15 years only,
here they will get
₹1 lakh for 15 years
and they are taking it as I have written, understand and for that they are
paying an annual premium
of ₹9263, so first of all what is the benefit, in the
first 4 years of the policy, you will
get a guaranteed addition at the rate of 3.5% of the total interest, which will amount to
Rs 14752 32 paise, right, after that, from the
fifth year onwards, simple reversal bonus will
start getting, now
if you have already seen the bonus PF on the Telegram channel,
then you will know that the bonus rate is
from 2 1/4% to 3.53%, the
bonus period will be of 10 years because it will be available from the
fifth year onwards, right, the bonus
period will be of 11 years
because my guaranteed addition is for the first 4 years of the policy,
after that, bonus can be received, right,
and the bonus rate we are assuming here is 2.5%,
so 1  If we take out 2.5% of one lakh and multiply it by 11, then the
simple reversionary bonus will be 27500. Right
here, now
cashback is also available before maturity and at the end of the third year, we will get
₹
10000. At the end of the 4th year of the policy, we will get ₹15000.
At the end of the 9th year of the policy, we will get
₹20000 and at the end of the 12th year of the policy, we will get ₹
25000. If we make 25% of one lakh, ₹25000 in total, then the
total cashback i.e. money back
amount that you will get will be ₹70000.
Right before maturity, we would have
received this much amount as money back.
We already know that the basic understanding is that
50% guaranteed addition of the basic sum measured plus our
vested simple reversionary bonus which accumulated
during the positive term, that becomes ₹50000.
Here, our 50% guaranteed addition of the basic sum measured is our right.
14752 rupees 32 paise and the wastage temple
reversal itself will eliminate the bonus of 27500,
their statement has also been given today, Mr. will get maturity benefits of 252 rupees 32 paise
and the policy will be banned, Dada
benefit, we know that if there is a socialist then the
mother gets it, Mr. If only one death occurs
with the policy on completion of the year, then the
amount of guaranteed addition which is for the
first 4 years of the policy at the rate of 3.5%,
if we apply
compound interest, we compound its components, then 14752 rupees 32, now see, bonus will be received at the end of the fifth year, at the end of the fourth year and within the seventh year, that is, bonus will be calculated here thrice, simple reversal of 7500 will become the
bonus, then what will be the judge benefit
here, our society is more, there is a
guaranteed addition of ₹1 lakh,
14752 rupees 32 paise bonus has come out,
7500 will be added here, then all three  If there will be a
benefit of ₹12000025232 here, then the
lump sum will be given to the nominee of Mr. A
and there will be a plain band here.
Okay, now let's talk about Mr.
Ji's comment.
After watching the video till here, Mr. Ji must have clearly understood
how to
calculate the benefit and the most
important thing is to calculate the benefit here,
all the main points because the
details of the bonus will be available to you on the Telegram channel, with
this you will calculate the guarantee addition and
bonus and Samajwadi,
you did not tell us in the comment area,
right, so we have shared the way of calculation with you. Rest, exactly,
for the people,
you should only contact the insurance company.
Thank you very much for watching the video till the end.
Thank you very much. Understand one thing yourself and
explain to others also that insurance
is a protection. Protection is never
taken incompletely. If you found the information clear, then
like and share the video, stay
connected with us by subscribing to the channel and take care of yourself.